<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adrià Mitjavila Ventura</title>
    <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adrià Mitjavila Ventura</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>chromHMMviewR</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/007-chromhmmviewr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/007-chromhmmviewr/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}   Adrià Mitjavila on March 23, 2021  Look at the source code here.
Goal chromHMMviewR is an R package to visualize data from ChromHMM.
After running chromHMM, I always had problems to integrate the results in my reports, so I started developping some functions to visualize the heatmaps that chromHMM shows you, but using ggplot2 instead. Finally, in order to practice the creation of R packages, I decided to follow these guides to turn the functions into a package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DPomics</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/006-dpomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/006-dpomics/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}   Adrià Mitjavila on March 5, 2021  DPomics: DP lab omics data visualization and integration.
Look at the source code here.
Goal DPomics is a ShinyAPP to visualize omics data coming from the analysis we do in our lab.
It has been made in order to be easy for the wetlab members to use it, hence I would like to deploy it to shinyapps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perill biològic</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/005-perillbiologic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/005-perillbiologic/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on February 10, 2021  I have recently started a blog named Perill Biològic.
The blog is entirely in catalan and is focussed to communicate general Biology knowledge to society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am not a virgin anymore!</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/004-xrn1_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/004-xrn1_paper/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on December 7, 2020   Figure 1: Figure 1 of the article showing the model of how Xrn1 and other RNA decay factors work. Source: Begley V et al (2020). Xrn1 influence on gene transcription results from the combination of general effects on elongating RNA pol II and gene-specific chromatin configuration. RNA Biology. doi: 10.1080/15476286.2020.1845504.  If you want to know more about it, read my post in BioBit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNAme</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/003-dname/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/003-dname/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on November 24, 2020  What is DNAme? DNAme is an application for teaching/learning purposes which converts a word to a DNA sequence. It has some theory to understand the processes underlying this conversion, but this theroy must not be used with teaching puroposes because it may have some inaccuracies. 
 How DNAme works? Summary DNAme was designed using R/Shiny that takes your name as a sequence of one-letter aminoacids and converts them to DNA/mRNA by looking for the codon that codes for each aminoacid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioBit</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/002-biobit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/002-biobit/</guid>
      <description>BioBit is a blog dedicated to spread and communicate bioinformatics to society. I made it using the R package distill and to publish it I used Netlify, because GitHub pages force me to have it as a subdomain of my personal website. My goal with the blog is posting basic things and recent advances about bioinformatics, as well as some biology and computer science -although I won’t post much about it, since I am a bioscientist rather than a computer one-.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biotechnologist around computers</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/001-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/001-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on November 11, 2020  At the beggining of my academic career, I wanted to be a wetlab scientist and, in honor to the truth, I didn’t love bioinformatics, so I focussed my bachelor’s thesis in Molecular Microbiology. However, I noticed how crucial informatics-based analyses of biological data are when we externally sequenced and processed our metagenomics data and when I had to make the statistical analysis all by myself without knowing any R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
