<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on ASBTEC</title>
    <link>https://asbtec.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on ASBTEC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ca</language><atom:link href="https://asbtec.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Istituto Europeo di Oncologia</title>
      <link>https://asbtec.github.io/research/003-ieo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asbtec.github.io/research/003-ieo/</guid>
      <description>  Pasini’s lab, Istituto Europeo di Oncologia July 2019 - Present
Bioinformatician and PhD student Insert research here My contribution to this research was:
Development of an ATACseq pipeline to run using Snakemake. The code can be visualized here. Analysis of transcriptomics (RNAseq), cistromics (ChIPseq) and DNA accessibility data (ATACseq).  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instituto de Biomedicina de Sevilla</title>
      <link>https://asbtec.github.io/research/002-ibis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asbtec.github.io/research/002-ibis/</guid>
      <description>Gene expression lab, Instituto de Biomedicina de Sevilla September 2017 - October 2018
Master’s thesis student and research assistant In the context of the master’s thesis (Universidad de Sevilla), under the supervision of Dr. Sebastián Chávez de Diego and Dr. Gabriel Gutierrez Pozo and within Dr. Victoria Begley’s PhD project, I started studying Xrn1, a protein involved in the degradation of mRNA, and it’s role in the nucleosome localization and transcription in Saccharomyces cerevisiae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbial. Sistemes i aplicacions analítiques, S.L.</title>
      <link>https://asbtec.github.io/research/001-microbial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asbtec.github.io/research/001-microbial/</guid>
      <description>Intestinal microbial ecology, Microbial, S.L. September 2016 - June 2017
Internship and Bachelor’s thesis student In the context of the bachelor’s thesis (Universitat de Girona) and under the supervision of Prof. Jesús García-Gil, I studied the diversity of the ileal mucosa-related microbiota of colorectal cancer patients submitted to an ileostomy and its changes after a butyrate treatment. Using DNA extracted from human biopsies of ileal mucosa, we performed qPCR and high-throughput sequencing followed by a SPSS-based statistical analysis of to test the differences between the butyrate-treated, placebo-treated and untreated groups, and we found that some healthy-related butyrate-producing bacteria increased in proportion after the butyrate-treated, but not in the other groups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
