<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adrià Mitjavila Ventura</title>
    <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adrià Mitjavila Ventura</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Institut Josep Carreras</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/004-ijc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/004-ijc/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}  Vavouri’s lab, Institut Josep Carreras August 2021 - Present
Bioinformatician &amp;amp; Master’s thesis student Under the supervision of Dr. Tanya Vavouri, I am studying the PIWI-interacting RNAs (piRNAs) and their biogenesis. I have recently completed a master’s thesis (MSc in Bioinformatics and Biostatistics) with honors, where I analyzed the piRNA variation across closely related species and the factors influencing this variation.
 My contributions to this research have been:   Analysis of smallRNA-seq data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istituto Europeo di Oncologia</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/003-ieo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/003-ieo/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}  Pasini’s lab, Istituto Europeo di Oncologia July 2019 - July 2021
Bioinformatician During my stage in Dr. Diego Pasini’s lab, I investigated several molecular signaling pathways and epigenetic mechanisms underlying cellular differentiation and oncogenesis.
 My contributions to this research were:   Comparison of different ATAC-seq peak callers.  Comparison of different sequencing depths in RNA-seq for differential expression analysis.  Development of a Snakemake pipepline for ATAC-seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instituto de Biomedicina de Sevilla</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/002-ibis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/002-ibis/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}  Gene expression lab, Instituto de Biomedicina de Sevilla September 2017 - October 2018
Master’s thesis student and research assistant In the context of the master’s thesis (MSc in Molecular Genetics &amp;amp; Biotechnology), under the supervision of Dr. Sebastián Chávez de Diego and Dr. Gabriel Gutierrez Pozo and within Dr. Victoria Begley’s PhD project, I started studying Xrn1, a protein involved in the degradation of mRNA, and it’s role in the nucleosome localization and transcription in Saccharomyces cerevisiae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbial. Sistemes i aplicacions analítiques, S.L.</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/001-microbial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/research/001-microbial/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}  Molecular Microbiology, Microbial, S.L. September 2016 - June 2017
Internship and Bachelor’s thesis student In the context of my bachelor’s thesis (BSc in Biotechnology) and under the supervision of Prof. Jesús García-Gil, I studied the diversity of the ileal mucosa-related microbiota of colorectal cancer patients submitted to an ileostomy and its changes after a butyrate treatment. Using DNA extracted from human biopsies of ileal mucosa, we performed qPCR and high-throughput sequencing followed by a SPSS-based statistical analysis to search for the differences between the butyrate-treated, placebo-treated and untreated groups, and we found that some healthy-related butyrate-producing bacteria increased in proportion after the butyrate-treated, but not in the other groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggmitji</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/009-ggmitji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/009-ggmitji/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}   Adrià Mitjavila on May 20, 2022  Look at the source code here.
Look at the documentation here.
ggmitji is an R package with cool functions to complement ggplots.
Dependencies ggmitji depends on several packages, such as: ggplot2, magrittr, polyclip, cowplot, and ggpubr.
 Functions Boxplots without outliers If you don’t like to show the outliers in your boxplots, you can use stat_summary_boxplot().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plotmics</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/008-plotmics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/008-plotmics/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}   Adrià Mitjavila on June 23, 2021 Edited on October 05, 2021  Look at the source code here.
Look at the documentation here.
plOtMICS is an R package to visualize omics and sequencing data in R using simple but useful functions:
 chromReads(): draws a ggplot2-based horizontal barplot with the number and the percentage of reads mapped to each chromosome. barDEGs(): draws a ggplot2-based horizontal barplot with the upregulated and downregulated genes coming from DESeq2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chromHMMviewR</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/007-chromhmmviewr_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/007-chromhmmviewr_/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}   Adrià Mitjavila on March 23, 2021  Look at the source code here.
Look at the documentation here.
Goal chromHMMviewR is an R package to visualize data from ChromHMM.
After running chromHMM, I always had problems to integrate the results in my reports, so I started developping some functions to visualize the heatmaps that chromHMM shows you, but using ggplot2 instead. Finally, in order to practice the creation of R packages, I decided to follow these guides to turn the functions into a package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DPomics</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/006-dpomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/006-dpomics/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}   Adrià Mitjavila on March 5, 2021  DPomics: DP lab omics data visualization and integration.
Look at the source code here.
Goal DPomics is a ShinyAPP to visualize omics data coming from the analysis we do in our lab.
It has been made in order to be easy for the wetlab members to use it, hence I would like to deploy it to shinyapps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perill biològic</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/005-perillbiologic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/005-perillbiologic/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on February 10, 2021  I have recently started a blog named Perill Biològic.
The blog is entirely in catalan and is focussed to communicate general Biology knowledge to society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am not a virgin anymore!</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/004-xrn1_paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/004-xrn1_paper/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on December 7, 2020   Figure 1: Figure 1 of the article showing the model of how Xrn1 and other RNA decay factors work. Source: Begley V et al (2020). Xrn1 influence on gene transcription results from the combination of general effects on elongating RNA pol II and gene-specific chromatin configuration. RNA Biology. doi: 10.1080/15476286.2020.1845504.  If you want to know more about it, read my post in BioBit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNAme</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/003-dname/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/003-dname/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on November 24, 2020  What is DNAme? DNAme is an application for teaching/learning purposes which converts a word to a DNA sequence. It has some theory to understand the processes underlying this conversion, but this theroy must not be used with teaching puroposes because it may have some inaccuracies. 
 How DNAme works? Summary DNAme was designed using R/Shiny that takes your name as a sequence of one-letter aminoacids and converts them to DNA/mRNA by looking for the codon that codes for each aminoacid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioBit</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/002-biobit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/002-biobit/</guid>
      <description>BioBit is a blog dedicated to spread and communicate bioinformatics to society. I made it using the R package distill and to publish it I used Netlify, because GitHub pages force me to have it as a subdomain of my personal website. My goal with the blog is posting basic things and recent advances about bioinformatics, as well as some biology and computer science -although I won’t post much about it, since I am a bioscientist rather than a computer one-.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biotechnologist around computers</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/001-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/posts/001-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Adrià Mitjavila on November 11, 2020  At the beggining of my academic career, I wanted to be a wetlab scientist and, in honor to the truth, I didn’t love bioinformatics, so I focussed my bachelor’s thesis in Molecular Microbiology. However, I noticed how crucial informatics-based analyses of biological data are when we externally sequenced and processed our metagenomics data and when I had to make the statistical analysis all by myself without knowing any R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}  Interests My interests are mainly focused in the analysis of transcriptomics and epigenomics data, as well as in software and pipeline development. Currently, I am interested in small RNAs, more specifically piRNAs
On the other hand, I declare myself as an R and R Markdown lover, but I am in an open relationship with them, so I am eager to learn and use other languages such as Bash and Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code development</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/code/</guid>
      <description>p {text-align: justify;}     Snakemake ATACseq Snakemake: Snakemake pipeline for ATAC-seq data processing and analyses used in Pasini’s lab. ongoing
 R Packages plotmics: functions to visualize omics and sequencing data.
ggmitji: cool functions for ggplots.
crhomHMMviewR: ggplot2-based functions that draw heatmaps from ChromHMM output data.
 Shiny apps DPomics: shiny app designed to visualize omics data from the Pasini Lab (RNA-seq and ChIP-seq). ongoing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitjavilaventura.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Journal articles Begley V et al (2020). Xrn1 influence on gene transcription results from the combination of general effects on elongating RNA pol II and gene-specific chromatin configuration. RNA Biology. doi: 10.1080/15476286.2020.1845504.
**Pre prints** --  Posters and presentations Mitjavila &amp;amp; Vavouri (March 2022). Analysis of piRNA variation across three Mus species (in Catalan). Oral presentation at the Jornades de Biologia de la Reproducció from the Catalan Society of Biology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
